### **Muhammad Usama Mashkoor**

Cell#: (92) 321 760 5414

Email: usamamashkoor@gmail.com

Current Address: Maple Block H# 132, Four Season Housing

Carrent talar coor maple block im 102) i car seas

Colony, Samundari Road Faisalabad, Pakistan

**Skype:** usama.mashkoor

# Profile:

Smart, intelligent and creative. Not an average type. I am an idea generator, a problem solver. Always think outside the box and not be afraid of breaking rules to be innovative, and to find the best solutions for problems. I have 7+ years of experience in application design and development. A self-motivated person with strong analytical. I strive for quality in everything I do and enjoy challenges and achieving goals. I work hard for recognition and aim to be a valuable employee and a great leader

### **Education:**

BS Computer Science (Hons) (2011-2015) CGPA => 3.56

GC University, Faisalabad

# **Key Skills:**

Backend Languages: Node.js, Node.js with TypeScript PHP, Python

Node.js Frameworks: Express.js, Keystone.js, Express.js with TypeScript

PHP Frameworks: Laravel, Codeigniter

Front End Frameworks: React, Redux using JavaScript (ES6), Vue.js, Next.js

• Database: MongoDB, MySQL, Amazon RDS, Amazon Aurora

• Project Management: Jira, Trello

Server Handling: Linux, Ubuntu, AWS (Amazon Web Services)

• Version Control: GitHub, Bitbucket

## Experience:

## Senior Software Engineer as a Full-Time Remote Worker (Jan 2017 - Present)

#### Responsibilities:

- Working on MERN Stack and Lamp Stack products as a Lead Developer, and also working in Python and PHP.
- Pure Agile project management implementation (using Jira)
- Develop Single Page Applications and Restful/Web services API
- Database designing and relationships.
- I have primarily worked in Node.js, Express.js, React.js, Redux, Vue.js, JavaScript (ES6) PHP, Laravel, MongoDB, and MySQL Database. I have also worked with AWS and Digital ocean servers.

# Senior Software Engineer at Devbox Private Limited Lahore (From MARCH 2016 - DEC 2016)

### Responsibilities:

- Worked as a PHP, Laravel, Angular.js, Ionic, and Facebook Graph Apo developer.
- Choosing the best tool & technology to meet project requirements for development.
- I have developed many applications in the domain of Healthcare, Retail, and Social Networks (Facebook Graph API) here
- Leading a small team of developers

# • Junior PHP Web Developer at Zepto System (Pvt) Ltd. Faisalabad (From May 2015 – Feb 2016)

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/usama-

mashkoor-a16a379a/

**GitHub:** <a href="https://github.com/usamamashkoor">https://github.com/usamamashkoor</a>

## Responsibilities:

- Worked as a PHP developer.
- Worked on the Pakistan Job Portal Right jobs.pk
- PHP Web Developer at DigitalSofts Private limited Faisalabad (From May 2014 May 2015)

# Responsibilities:

- Worked as a PHP developer.
- Worked on the ERP projects using Laravel

### Projects:

# • SaaS application for the property tax calculation (https://propertyaxe.com/)

**Responsibilities:** Converted the Figma designs to React.js and then created the backend of the application using REST API in Node.js

#### Introduction:

PropertyAxe is a platform, where users can search their properties, and then they can see their property comparisons when their property comparisons are generated, then we show them on Google Maps so that they can see, which other properties' tax is less than their property, in the end, they can enter their protest and can generate an evidence packet to support their protest.

# Technologies:

- MERN STACK, Express.js, React, Redux, MongoDB, Redux Thunk, Node.js, Socket.io, Amazon Web Services, Git, Stripe, AWS, EC2, S3, AWS Incognito.
- Defisignals Cryptocurrency Marketplace (https://trade.defisignals.io/)

**Responsibilities:** I have taken all the requirements from my client and then created the single page application using MERN Stack and created the bot servers in Node.js and then created webhooks using Python Fast API.

#### Introduction:

 Defisignals is a cryptocurrency marketplace where you can buy and sell cryptocurrency and with our improved algorithms, we can notify you when you should Buy and sell the cryptocurrency so that you can get maximum profit.

### Technologies:

 MERN STACK, Express.js, React, Redux, MongoDB, Redux Thunk, Node.js, Socket.io, Amazon Web Services, Git, Stripe, AWS, EC2, S3, AWS Incognito, Discord Bot, Telegram Bot, Python, Fast API, Binance API, Ftx API.

### JUBZI (SOFOS.JUBZI.COM)

**Responsibilities:** I have taken all the requirements from my client and then created the single page application using MERN Stack. I have developed this app from scratch and I have deployed this app using AWS.

#### Introduction:

Online ordering website that, offers a way for his customers to place online orders from the website.

# Technologies:

 MERN STACK, Express.js, React, Redux, MongoDB, Redux Thunk, Node.js, Socket.io, Amazon Web Services, Git, Stripe, AWS, EC2, S3, AWS Incognito.

### • JUBZI (https://jubzi.com) SAAS Mobile Ordering Platform

# Introduction:

Jubzi, is a SaaS platform, On Which restaurants get registered and add their menus, and users can place
orders on restaurants and restaurants can check the orders on their Point of sale which we have
developed for them.

**Responsibilities:** I have taken all the requirements from my client and then created the single page application using MERN Stack. I have developed this app from scratch and I have deployed this app using AWS.

# Technologies:

MERN STACK, Express.js, React, Redux, MongoDB, Redux Thunk, Node.js, Socket.io, Amazon Web Services, Git, Stripe, AWS, EC2, S3, AWS Incognito, Twilio, Stripe.

# • RIGHTJOBS.PK (WEB APP)

# Technologies:

- PHP, Codeigniter, MySQL, HMVC, Restful APIs, JavaScript, jQuery, JavaScript Design Patterns, PHP Smarty, Store Procedures, and SVN.
- RightJobs is a Pakistan online job portal where job seekers can apply for jobs and employers can post jobs. I have created this application with a team of developers and also created its Restful APIs for the Android and IOS applications.

# Interests:

Machine Learning, Big Data, Blockchain